<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="array_assign" kind="page">
    <compoundname>array_assign</compoundname>
    <title>ASSIGN Making assignments</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_array_1sec_array" kindref="member">Array Generation and Manipulations</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>FreeMat assignments take a number of different forms, depending on the type of the variable you want to make an assignment to. For numerical arrays and strings, the form of an assignment is either <verbatim>  a(ndx) = val
</verbatim> where <computeroutput>ndx</computeroutput> is a set of vector indexing coordinates. This means that the values <computeroutput>ndx</computeroutput> takes reference the elements of <computeroutput>a</computeroutput> in column order. So, if, for example <computeroutput>a</computeroutput> is an <computeroutput>N x M</computeroutput> matrix, the first column has vector indices <computeroutput>1,2,...,N</computeroutput>, and the second column has indices <computeroutput>N+1,N+2,...,2N</computeroutput>, and so on. Alternately, you can use multi-dimensional indexing to make an assignment: <verbatim>  a(ndx_1,ndx_2,..,ndx_m) = val
</verbatim> where each indexing expression <computeroutput>ndx_i</computeroutput> corresponds to the <computeroutput>i-th</computeroutput> dimension of <computeroutput>a</computeroutput>. In both cases, (vector or multi-dimensional indexing), the right hand side <computeroutput>val</computeroutput> must either be a scalar, an empty matrix, or of the same size as the indices. If <computeroutput>val</computeroutput> is an empty matrix, the assignment acts like a delete. Note that the type of <computeroutput>a</computeroutput> may be modified by the assignment. So, for example, assigning a <computeroutput>double</computeroutput> value to an element of a <computeroutput>float</computeroutput> array <computeroutput>a</computeroutput> will cause the array <computeroutput>a</computeroutput> to become <computeroutput>double</computeroutput>.</para><para>For cell arrays, the above forms of assignment will still work, but only if <computeroutput>val</computeroutput> is also a cell array. If you want to assign the contents of a cell in a cell array, you must use one of the two following forms, either <verbatim>  a{ndx} = val
</verbatim> or <verbatim>  a{ndx_1,ndx_2,...,ndx_m} = val
</verbatim> which will modify the contents of the cell. </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
