<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="freemat_rootpath" kind="page">
    <compoundname>freemat_rootpath</compoundname>
    <title>ROOTPATH Set FreeMat Root Path</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_freemat_1sec_freemat" kindref="member">FreeMat Functions</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>In order to function properly, FreeMat needs to know where to find the <computeroutput>toolbox</computeroutput> directory as well as the <computeroutput>help</computeroutput> directory. These directories are located on what is known as the <computeroutput>root path</computeroutput>. Normally, FreeMat should know where these directories are located. However under some circumstances (usually when FreeMat is installed into a non-default location), it may be necessary to indicate a different root path location, or to specify a particular one. Note that on the Mac OS platform, FreeMat is installed as a bundle, and will use the toolbox that is installed in the bundle regardless of the setting for <computeroutput>rootpath</computeroutput>. For Linux, FreeMat will typically use <computeroutput>/usr/local/share/FreeMat-&lt;Version&gt;/</computeroutput> for the root path. Installations from source code will generally work, but binary installations (e.g., from an <computeroutput>RPM</computeroutput>) may need to have the rootpath set.</para><para>The <computeroutput>rootpath</computeroutput> function has two forms. The first form takes no arguments and returns the current root path <verbatim>   rootpath
</verbatim> The second form will set a rootpath directly from the command line <verbatim>   rootpath(path)
</verbatim> where <computeroutput>path</computeroutput> is the full path to where the <computeroutput>toolbox</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>help</computeroutput> directories are located. For example, <computeroutput>rootpath(&apos;/usr/share/FreeMat-4.0&apos;)</computeroutput>. The third form enables the GUI form <verbatim>   rootpath gui
</verbatim> which activates a dialog box to pick a directory that is the root directory of the FreeMat installation (e.g., where <computeroutput>help</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>toolbox</computeroutput> are located. Changes to <computeroutput>rootpath</computeroutput> are persistent (you do not need to run it every time you start FreeMat). </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
