<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="freemat_diary" kind="page">
    <compoundname>freemat_diary</compoundname>
    <title>DIARY Create a Log File of Console</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_freemat_1sec_freemat" kindref="member">FreeMat Functions</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>The <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput> function controls the creation of a log file that duplicates the text that would normally appear on the console. The simplest syntax for the command is simply: <verbatim>   diary
</verbatim> which toggles the current state of the diary command. You can also explicitly set the state of the diary command via the syntax <verbatim>   diary off
</verbatim> or <verbatim>   diary on
</verbatim> To specify a filename for the log (other than the default of <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput>), you can use the form: <verbatim>   diary filename
</verbatim> or <verbatim>   diary(&apos;filename&apos;)
</verbatim> which activates the diary with an output filename of <computeroutput>filename</computeroutput>. Note that the <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput> command is thread specific, but that the output is appended to a given file. That means that if you call <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput> with the same filename on multiple threads, their outputs will be intermingled in the log file (just as on the console). Because the <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput> state is tied to individual threads, you cannot retrieve the current diary state using the <computeroutput>get(0,&apos;Diary&apos;)</computeroutput> syntax from MATLAB. Instead, you must call the <computeroutput>diary</computeroutput> function with no inputs and one output: <verbatim>   state = diary
</verbatim> which returns a logical <computeroutput>1</computeroutput> if the output of the current thread is currently going to a diary, and a logical <computeroutput>0</computeroutput> if not. </para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
