<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="handle_imageproperties" kind="page">
    <compoundname>handle_imageproperties</compoundname>
    <title>IMAGEPROPERTIES Image Object Properties</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_handle_1sec_handle" kindref="member">Handle-Based Graphics</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>Below is a summary of the properties for the axis. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>alphadata</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>vector</computeroutput> - This is a vector that should contain as many elements as the image data itself <computeroutput>cdata</computeroutput>, or a single scalar. For a single scalar, all values of the image take on the same transparency. Otherwise, the transparency of each pixel is determined by the corresponding value from the <computeroutput>alphadata</computeroutput> vector.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>alphadatamapping</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>{&apos;scaled&apos;,&apos;direct&apos;,&apos;none&apos;}</computeroutput> - For <computeroutput>none</computeroutput> mode (the default), no transparency is applied to the data. For <computeroutput>direct</computeroutput> mode, the vector <computeroutput>alphadata</computeroutput> contains values between @[0,M-1]| where <computeroutput>M</computeroutput> is the length of the alpha map stored in the figure. For <computeroutput>scaled</computeroutput> mode, the <computeroutput>alim</computeroutput> vector for the figure is used to linearly rescale the alpha data prior to lookup in the alpha map.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>cdata</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>array</computeroutput> - This is either a <computeroutput>M x N</computeroutput> array or an <computeroutput>M x N x 3</computeroutput> array. If the data is <computeroutput>M x N</computeroutput> the image is a scalar image (indexed mode), where the color associated with each image pixel is computed using the colormap and the <computeroutput>cdatamapping</computeroutput> mode. If the data is <computeroutput>M x N x 3</computeroutput> the image is assumed to be in RGB mode, and the colorpanes are taken directly from <computeroutput>cdata</computeroutput> (the colormap is ignored). Note that in this case, the data values must be between @[0,1]| for each color channel and each pixel.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>cdatamapping</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>{&apos;scaled&apos;,&apos;direct&apos;}</computeroutput> - For <computeroutput>scaled</computeroutput> (the default), the pixel values are scaled using the <computeroutput>clim</computeroutput> vector for the figure prior to looking up in the colormap. For <computeroutput>direct</computeroutput> mode, the pixel values must be in the range <computeroutput>[0,N-1</computeroutput> where <computeroutput>N</computeroutput> is the number of colors in the colormap if the data is integer type. For floating point data types, values must be in the range <computeroutput>[1,N]</computeroutput>.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>children</computeroutput> - Not used.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>parent</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>handle</computeroutput> - The axis containing the image.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>tag</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>string</computeroutput> - You can set this to any string you want.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>type</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>string</computeroutput> - Set to the string <computeroutput>&apos;image&apos;</computeroutput>.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>xdata</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>two vector</computeroutput> - contains the x coordinates of the first and last column (respectively). Defaults to <computeroutput>[1,C]</computeroutput> where <computeroutput>C</computeroutput> is the number of columns in the image.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>ydata</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>two vector</computeroutput> - contains the y coordinates of the first and last row (respectively). Defaults to <computeroutput>[1,R]</computeroutput> where <computeroutput>R</computeroutput> is the number of rows in the image.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>userdata</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>array</computeroutput> - Available to store any variable you want in the handle object.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>visible</computeroutput> - <computeroutput>{&apos;on&apos;,&apos;off&apos;}</computeroutput> - Controls whether the image is visible or not.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
