<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkcommon_vtkpolynomialsolversunivariate" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkcommon_vtkpolynomialsolversunivariate</compoundname>
    <title>vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkcommon_1sec_vtkcommon" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Common Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate provides solvers for univariate polynomial equations with real coefficients. The Tartaglia-Cardan and Ferrari solvers work on polynomials of fixed degree 3 and 4, respectively. The Lin-Bairstow and Sturm solvers work on polynomials of arbitrary degree. The Sturm solver is the most robust solver but only reports roots within an interval and does not report multiplicities. The Lin-Bairstow solver reports multiplicities.</para><para>For difficult polynomials, you may wish to use FilterRoots to eliminate some of the roots reported by the Sturm solver. FilterRoots evaluates the derivatives near each root to eliminate cases where a local minimum or maximum is close to zero.</para><para>.SECTION Thanks Thanks to Philippe Pebay, Korben Rusek, David Thompson, and Maurice Rojas for implementing these solvers.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPolynomialSolversUnivariate = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
