<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkfiltering_vtkcompositedatapipeline" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkfiltering_vtkcompositedatapipeline</compoundname>
    <title>vtkCompositeDataPipeline</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkfiltering_1sec_vtkfiltering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Filtering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkCompositeDataPipeline is an executive that supports the processing of composite dataset. It supports algorithms that are aware of composite dataset as well as those that are not. Type checking is performed at run time. Algorithms that are not composite dataset-aware have to support all dataset types contained in the composite dataset. The pipeline execution can be summarized as follows:</para><para>REQUEST_INFORMATION: The producers have to provide information about the contents of the composite dataset in this pass. Sources that can produce more than one piece (note that a piece is different than a block; each piece consistes of 0 or more blocks) should set MAXIMUM_NUMBER_OF_PIECES to -1.</para><para>REQUEST_UPDATE_EXTENT: This pass is identical to the one implemented in vtkStreamingDemandDrivenPipeline</para><para>REQUEST_DATA: This is where the algorithms execute. If the vtkCompositeDataPipeline is assigned to a simple filter, it will invoke the vtkStreamingDemandDrivenPipeline passes in a loop, passing a different block each time and will collect the results in a composite dataset. .SECTION See also vtkCompositeDataSet</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkCompositeDataPipeline, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkCompositeDataPipeline
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkCompositeDataPipeline has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkCompositeDataPipeline class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkCompositeDataPipeline = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkCompositeDataPipeline = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkDataObject = obj.GetCompositeOutputData (int port)</computeroutput> - Returns the data object stored with the DATA_OBJECT() in the output port  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
