<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkfiltering_vtkabstractpointlocator" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkfiltering_vtkabstractpointlocator</compoundname>
    <title>vtkAbstractPointLocator</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkfiltering_1sec_vtkfiltering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Filtering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkAbstractPointLocator is an abstract spatial search object to quickly locate points in 3D. vtkAbstractPointLocator works by dividing a specified region of space into &quot;rectangular&quot; buckets, and then keeping a list of points that lie in each bucket. Typical operation involves giving a position in 3D and finding the closest point. The points are provided from the specified dataset input.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkAbstractPointLocator, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkAbstractPointLocator
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkAbstractPointLocator has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkAbstractPointLocator class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAbstractPointLocator = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAbstractPointLocator = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkIdType = obj.FindClosestPoint (double x[3])</computeroutput> - Given a position x, return the id of the point closest to it. Alternative method requires separate x-y-z values. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkIdType = obj.FindClosestPoint (double x, double y, double z)</computeroutput> - Given a position x, return the id of the point closest to it. Alternative method requires separate x-y-z values. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.FindClosestNPoints (int N, double x[3], vtkIdList result)</computeroutput> - Find the closest N points to a position. This returns the closest N points to a position. A faster method could be created that returned N close points to a position, but necessarily the exact N closest. The returned points are sorted from closest to farthest. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.FindClosestNPoints (int N, double x, double y, double z, vtkIdList result)</computeroutput> - Find the closest N points to a position. This returns the closest N points to a position. A faster method could be created that returned N close points to a position, but necessarily the exact N closest. The returned points are sorted from closest to farthest. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.FindPointsWithinRadius (double R, double x[3], vtkIdList result)</computeroutput> - Find all points within a specified radius R of position x. The result is not sorted in any specific manner. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.FindPointsWithinRadius (double R, double x, double y, double z, vtkIdList result)</computeroutput> - Find all points within a specified radius R of position x. The result is not sorted in any specific manner. These methods are thread safe if BuildLocator() is directly or indirectly called from a single thread first.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.GetBounds (double )</computeroutput> - Provide an accessor to the bounds.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.FreeSearchStructure ()</computeroutput> - See vtkLocator interface documentation. These methods are not thread safe.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.BuildLocator ()</computeroutput> - See vtkLocator interface documentation. These methods are not thread safe.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.GenerateRepresentation (int level, vtkPolyData pd)</computeroutput> - See vtkLocator interface documentation. These methods are not thread safe.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
