<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkfiltering_vtkpointsettopointsetfilter" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkfiltering_vtkpointsettopointsetfilter</compoundname>
    <title>vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkfiltering_1sec_vtkfiltering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Filtering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter is an abstract filter class whose subclasses take as input a point set and generates a point set on output. At a minimum, the concrete subclasses of vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter modify their point coordinates. They never modify their topological form, however.</para><para>This is an abstract filter type. What that means is that the output of the filter is an abstract type (i.e., vtkPointSet), no matter what the input of the filter is. This can cause problems connecting together filters due to the change in dataset type. (For example, in a series of filters processing vtkPolyData, when a vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter or subclass is introduced into the pipeline, if the filter downstream of it takes vtkPolyData as input, the pipeline connection cannot be made.) To get around this problem, use one of the convenience methods to return a concrete type (e.g., vtkGetPolyDataOutput(), GetStructuredGridOutput(), etc.).</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPointSetToPointSetFilter = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInput (vtkPointSet input)</computeroutput> - Specify the input data or filter.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPointSet = obj.GetInput ()</computeroutput> - Get the input data or filter.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPointSet = obj.GetOutput ()</computeroutput> - Get the output of this filter. If output is NULL, then input hasn&apos;t been set, which is necessary for abstract filter objects.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPointSet = obj.GetOutput (int idx)</computeroutput> - Get the output as vtkPolyData. Performs run-time checking.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkPolyData = obj.GetPolyDataOutput ()</computeroutput> - Get the output as vtkPolyData. Performs run-time checking.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkStructuredGrid = obj.GetStructuredGridOutput ()</computeroutput> - Get the output as vtkStructuredGrid. Performs run-time checking.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkUnstructuredGrid = obj.GetUnstructuredGridOutput ()</computeroutput> - Get the output as vtkUnstructuredGrid. Performs run-time checking.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.ComputeInputUpdateExtents (vtkDataObject output)</computeroutput> - By default copy the output update extent to the input  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
