<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkfiltering_vtkannotationlayers" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkfiltering_vtkannotationlayers</compoundname>
    <title>vtkAnnotationLayers</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkfiltering_1sec_vtkfiltering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Filtering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkAnnotationLayers stores a vector of annotation layers. Each layer may contain any number of vtkAnnotation objects. The ordering of the layers introduces a prioritization of annotations. Annotations in higher layers may obscure annotations in lower layers.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkAnnotationLayers, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkAnnotationLayers
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkAnnotationLayers has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkAnnotationLayers class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAnnotationLayers = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAnnotationLayers = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetCurrentAnnotation (vtkAnnotation ann)</computeroutput> - The current annotation associated with this annotation link.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAnnotation = obj.GetCurrentAnnotation ()</computeroutput> - The current annotation associated with this annotation link.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetCurrentSelection (vtkSelection sel)</computeroutput> - The current selection associated with this annotation link. This is simply the selection contained in the current annotation.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkSelection = obj.GetCurrentSelection ()</computeroutput> - The current selection associated with this annotation link. This is simply the selection contained in the current annotation.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetNumberOfAnnotations ()</computeroutput> - The number of annotations in a specific layer.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAnnotation = obj.GetAnnotation (int idx)</computeroutput> - Retrieve an annotation from a layer.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AddAnnotation (vtkAnnotation ann)</computeroutput> - Add an annotation to a layer.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.RemoveAnnotation (vtkAnnotation ann)</computeroutput> - Remove an annotation from a layer.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.Initialize ()</computeroutput> - Initialize the data structure to an empty state.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.ShallowCopy (vtkDataObject other)</computeroutput> - Copy data from another data object into this one which references the same member annotations.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.DeepCopy (vtkDataObject other)</computeroutput> - Copy data from another data object into this one, performing a deep copy of member annotations.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>long = obj.GetMTime ()</computeroutput> - The modified time for this object.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
