<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkgraphics_vtksplitfield" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkgraphics_vtksplitfield</compoundname>
    <title>vtkSplitField</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkgraphics_1sec_vtkgraphics" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Graphics Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkSplitField is used to split a multi-component field (vtkDataArray) into multiple single component fields. The new fields are put in the same field data as the original field. The output arrays are of the same type as the input array. Example: <verbatim> sf-&gt;SetInputField(&quot;gradient&quot;, vtkSplitField::POINT_DATA);
 sf-&gt;Split(0, &quot;firstcomponent&quot;);</verbatim> tells vtkSplitField to extract the first component of the field called gradient and create an array called firstcomponent (the new field will be in the output&apos;s point data). The same can be done from Tcl: <verbatim> sf SetInputField gradient POINT_DATA
 sf Split 0 firstcomponent

 AttributeTypes: SCALARS, VECTORS, NORMALS, TCOORDS, TENSORS
 Field locations: DATA_OBJECT, POINT_DATA, CELL_DATA</verbatim> Note that, by default, the original array is also passed through.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkSplitField, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkSplitField
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkSplitField has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkSplitField class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkSplitField = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkSplitField = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputField (int attributeType, int fieldLoc)</computeroutput> - Use the given attribute in the field data given by fieldLoc as input.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputField (string name, int fieldLoc)</computeroutput> - Use the array with given name in the field data given by fieldLoc as input.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputField (string name, string fieldLoc)</computeroutput> - Helper method used by other language bindings. Allows the caller to specify arguments as strings instead of enums.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.Split (int component, string arrayName)</computeroutput> - Create a new array with the given component.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
