<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkhybrid_vtkexodusmodel" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkhybrid_vtkexodusmodel</compoundname>
    <title>vtkExodusModel</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkhybrid_1sec_vtkhybrid" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Hybrid Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>A vtkUnstructuredGrid output by vtkExodusReader or vtkPExodusReader is missing a great deal of initialization and static model data that is in an Exodus II file. (Global variables, properties, node sets, side sets, and so on.) This data can be stored in a vtkModelMetadata object, which can be initialized using this vtkExodusModel class.</para><para>This class can be initialized with a file handle for an open Exodus file, and the vtkUnstructuredGrid derived from that file. The methods used would be SetGlobalInformation, SetLocalInformation, AddUGridElementVariable and AddUGridNodeVariable. The vtkExodusReader does this.</para><para>It can also be initialized (using UnpackExodusModel) from a vtkUnstructuredGrid that has had metadata packed into it&apos;s field arrays with PackExodusModel. The vtkExodusIIWriter does this.</para><para>If you plan to write out the Exodus file (with vtkExodusIIWriter), you should direct the Exodus reader to create a vtkExodusModel object. This will be used by the Exodus writer to create a correct Exodus II file on output. In addition, the vtkDistributedDataFilter is cognizant of the ExodusModel object and will unpack, extract, merge, and pack these objects associated with the grids it is partitioning.</para><para>.SECTION See also vtkExodusReader vtkPExodusReader vtkExodusIIWriter vtkModelMetadata vtkDistributedDataFilter</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkExodusModel, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkExodusModel
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkExodusModel has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkExodusModel class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkExodusModel = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkExodusModel = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.SetGlobalInformation (int fid, int compute_word_size)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddUGridElementVariable (string ugridVarName, string origName, int numComponents)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.RemoveUGridElementVariable (string ugridVarName)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddUGridNodeVariable (string ugridVarName, string origName, int numComponents)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.RemoveUGridNodeVariable (string ugridVarName)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.SetLocalInformation (vtkUnstructuredGrid ugrid, int fid, int timeStep, int newGeometry, int compute_word_size)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkModelMetadata = obj.GetModelMetadata ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetModelMetadata (vtkModelMetadata emData)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.UnpackExodusModel (vtkUnstructuredGrid grid, int deleteIt)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.MergeExodusModel (vtkExodusModel em)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkExodusModel = obj.ExtractExodusModel (vtkIdTypeArray globalCellIdList, vtkUnstructuredGrid grid)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.PackExodusModel (vtkUnstructuredGrid grid)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.Reset ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
