<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkinfovis_vtkcomputehistogram2doutliers" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkinfovis_vtkcomputehistogram2doutliers</compoundname>
    <title>vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkinfovis_1sec_vtkinfovis" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Infovis Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>This class takes a table and one or more vtkImageData histograms as input and computes the outliers in that data. In general it does so by identifying histogram bins that are removed by a median (salt and pepper) filter and below a threshold. This threshold is automatically identified to retrieve a number of outliers close to a user-determined value. This value is set by calling SetPreferredNumberOfOutliers(int).</para><para>The image data input can come either as a multiple vtkImageData via the repeatable INPUT_HISTOGRAM_IMAGE_DATA port, or as a single vtkMultiBlockDataSet containing vtkImageData objects as blocks. One or the other must be set, not both (or neither).</para><para>The output can be retrieved as a set of row ids in a vtkSelection or as a vtkTable containing the actual outlier row data.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkComputeHistogram2DOutliers = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetPreferredNumberOfOutliers (int )</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetPreferredNumberOfOutliers ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkTable = obj.GetOutputTable ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputTableConnection (vtkAlgorithmOutput cxn)</computeroutput> - Set the input histogram data as a (repeatable) vtkImageData  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputHistogramImageDataConnection (vtkAlgorithmOutput cxn)</computeroutput> - Set the input histogram data as a vtkMultiBlockData set containing multiple vtkImageData objects.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetInputHistogramMultiBlockConnection (vtkAlgorithmOutput cxn)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
