<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkimaging_vtkimagecontinuouserode3d" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkimaging_vtkimagecontinuouserode3d</compoundname>
    <title>vtkImageContinuousErode3D</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkimaging_1sec_vtkimaging" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Imaging Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkImageContinuousErode3D replaces a pixel with the minimum over an ellipsoidal neighborhood. If KernelSize of an axis is 1, no processing is done on that axis.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkImageContinuousErode3D, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkImageContinuousErode3D
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkImageContinuousErode3D has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkImageContinuousErode3D class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput> - Construct an instance of vtkImageContinuousErode3D filter. By default zero values are eroded.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput> - Construct an instance of vtkImageContinuousErode3D filter. By default zero values are eroded.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkImageContinuousErode3D = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput> - Construct an instance of vtkImageContinuousErode3D filter. By default zero values are eroded.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkImageContinuousErode3D = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput> - Construct an instance of vtkImageContinuousErode3D filter. By default zero values are eroded.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetKernelSize (int size0, int size1, int size2)</computeroutput> - This method sets the size of the neighborhood. It also sets the default middle of the neighborhood and computes the elliptical foot print.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
