<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkinfovis_vtkcorrelativestatistics" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkinfovis_vtkcorrelativestatistics</compoundname>
    <title>vtkCorrelativeStatistics</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkinfovis_1sec_vtkinfovis" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Infovis Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>Given a selection of pairs of columns of interest, this class provides the following functionalities, depending on the execution mode it is executed in: Learn: calculate means, unbiased variance and covariance estimators of column pairs, and corresponding linear regressions and linear correlation coefficient. More precisely, Learn calculates the sums; if <computeroutput>finalize</computeroutput> is set to true (default), the final statistics are calculated with the function CalculateFromSums. Otherwise, only raw sums are output; this option is made for efficient parallel calculations. Note that CalculateFromSums is a static function, so that it can be used directly with no need to instantiate a vtkCorrelativeStatistics object. Assess: given two data vectors X and Y with the same number of entries as input in port INPUT_DATA, and reference means, variances, and covariance, along with an acceptable threshold t&gt;1, assess all pairs of values of (X,Y) whose relative PDF (assuming a bivariate Gaussian model) is below t.</para><para>.SECTION Thanks Thanks to Philippe Pebay and David Thompson from Sandia National Laboratories for implementing this class.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkCorrelativeStatistics, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkCorrelativeStatistics
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkCorrelativeStatistics has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkCorrelativeStatistics class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkCorrelativeStatistics = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkCorrelativeStatistics = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.Aggregate (vtkDataObjectCollection , vtkDataObject )</computeroutput> - Given a collection of models, calculate aggregate model  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
