<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkio_vtkxmlparser" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkio_vtkxmlparser</compoundname>
    <title>vtkXMLParser</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkio_1sec_vtkio" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit IO Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkXMLParser reads a stream and parses XML element tags and corresponding attributes. Each element begin tag and its attributes are sent to the StartElement method. Each element end tag is sent to the EndElement method. Subclasses should replace these methods to actually use the tags. .SECTION ToDo: Add commands for parsing in Tcl.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkXMLParser, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkXMLParser
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkXMLParser has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkXMLParser class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkXMLParser = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkXMLParser = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>long = obj.TellG ()</computeroutput> - Used by subclasses and their supporting classes. These methods wrap around the tellg and seekg methods of the input stream to work-around stream bugs on various platforms.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SeekG (long position)</computeroutput> - Used by subclasses and their supporting classes. These methods wrap around the tellg and seekg methods of the input stream to work-around stream bugs on various platforms.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.Parse ()</computeroutput> - Parse the XML input.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.Parse (string inputString)</computeroutput> - Parse the XML message. If length is specified, parse only the first &quot;length&quot; characters  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.Parse (string inputString, int length)</computeroutput> - Parse the XML message. If length is specified, parse only the first &quot;length&quot; characters  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.InitializeParser ()</computeroutput> - When parsing fragments of XML or streaming XML, use the following three methods. InitializeParser method initialize parser but does not perform any actual parsing. ParseChunk parses framgent of XML. This has to match to what was already parsed. CleanupParser finishes parsing. If there were errors, CleanupParser will report them.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.ParseChunk (string inputString, int length)</computeroutput> - When parsing fragments of XML or streaming XML, use the following three methods. InitializeParser method initialize parser but does not perform any actual parsing. ParseChunk parses framgent of XML. This has to match to what was already parsed. CleanupParser finishes parsing. If there were errors, CleanupParser will report them.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.CleanupParser ()</computeroutput> - When parsing fragments of XML or streaming XML, use the following three methods. InitializeParser method initialize parser but does not perform any actual parsing. ParseChunk parses framgent of XML. This has to match to what was already parsed. CleanupParser finishes parsing. If there were errors, CleanupParser will report them.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetFileName (string )</computeroutput> - Set and get file name.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetFileName ()</computeroutput> - Set and get file name.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetIgnoreCharacterData (int )</computeroutput> - If this is off (the default), CharacterDataHandler will be called to process text within XML Elements. If this is on, the text will be ignored.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetIgnoreCharacterData ()</computeroutput> - If this is off (the default), CharacterDataHandler will be called to process text within XML Elements. If this is on, the text will be ignored.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetEncoding (string )</computeroutput> - Set and get the encoding the parser should expect (NULL defaults to Expat&apos;s own default encoder, i.e UTF-8). This should be set before parsing (i.e. a call to Parse()) or even initializing the parser (i.e. a call to InitializeParser())  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetEncoding ()</computeroutput> - Set and get the encoding the parser should expect (NULL defaults to Expat&apos;s own default encoder, i.e UTF-8). This should be set before parsing (i.e. a call to Parse()) or even initializing the parser (i.e. a call to InitializeParser())  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
