<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkio_vtkmincimagewriter" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkio_vtkmincimagewriter</compoundname>
    <title>vtkMINCImageWriter</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkio_1sec_vtkio" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit IO Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>MINC is a NetCDF-based medical image file format that was developed at the Montreal Neurological Institute in 1992. The data is written slice-by-slice, and this writer is therefore suitable for streaming MINC data that is larger than the memory size through VTK. This writer can also produce files with up to 4 dimensions, where the fourth dimension is provided by using AddInput() to specify multiple input data sets. If you want to set header information for the file, you must supply a vtkMINCImageAttributes</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkMINCImageWriter, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkMINCImageWriter
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkMINCImageWriter has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkMINCImageWriter class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkMINCImageWriter = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkMINCImageWriter = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetFileExtensions ()</computeroutput> - Get the name of this file format.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetDescriptiveName ()</computeroutput> - Set the file name.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetFileName (string name)</computeroutput> - Set the file name.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.Write ()</computeroutput> - Write the data. This will attempt to stream the data slice-by-slice through the pipeline and out to the file, unless the whole extent of the input has already been updated.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetDirectionCosines (vtkMatrix4x4 matrix)</computeroutput> - Set a matrix that describes the orientation of the data. The three columns of this matrix should give the unit-vector directions for the VTK x, y and z dimensions respectively. The writer will use this information to determine how to map the VTK dimensions to the canonical MINC dimensions, and if necessary, the writer will re-order one or more dimensions back-to-front to ensure that no MINC dimension ends up with a direction cosines vector whose dot product with the canonical unit vector for that dimension is negative.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkMatrix4x4 = obj.GetDirectionCosines ()</computeroutput> - Set a matrix that describes the orientation of the data. The three columns of this matrix should give the unit-vector directions for the VTK x, y and z dimensions respectively. The writer will use this information to determine how to map the VTK dimensions to the canonical MINC dimensions, and if necessary, the writer will re-order one or more dimensions back-to-front to ensure that no MINC dimension ends up with a direction cosines vector whose dot product with the canonical unit vector for that dimension is negative.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetRescaleSlope (double )</computeroutput> - Set the slope and intercept for rescaling the intensities. The default values are zero, which indicates to the reader that no rescaling is to be performed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetRescaleSlope ()</computeroutput> - Set the slope and intercept for rescaling the intensities. The default values are zero, which indicates to the reader that no rescaling is to be performed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetRescaleIntercept (double )</computeroutput> - Set the slope and intercept for rescaling the intensities. The default values are zero, which indicates to the reader that no rescaling is to be performed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetRescaleIntercept ()</computeroutput> - Set the slope and intercept for rescaling the intensities. The default values are zero, which indicates to the reader that no rescaling is to be performed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetImageAttributes (vtkMINCImageAttributes attributes)</computeroutput> - Set the image attributes, which contain patient information and other useful metadata.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkMINCImageAttributes = obj.GetImageAttributes ()</computeroutput> - Set the image attributes, which contain patient information and other useful metadata.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetStrictValidation (int )</computeroutput> - Set whether to validate that all variable attributes that have been set are ones that are listed in the MINC standard.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.StrictValidationOn ()</computeroutput> - Set whether to validate that all variable attributes that have been set are ones that are listed in the MINC standard.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.StrictValidationOff ()</computeroutput> - Set whether to validate that all variable attributes that have been set are ones that are listed in the MINC standard.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetStrictValidation ()</computeroutput> - Set whether to validate that all variable attributes that have been set are ones that are listed in the MINC standard.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetHistoryAddition (string )</computeroutput> - Set a string value to append to the history of the file. This string should describe, briefly, how the file was processed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetHistoryAddition ()</computeroutput> - Set a string value to append to the history of the file. This string should describe, briefly, how the file was processed.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
