<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkrendering_vtkgenericvertexattributemapping" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkrendering_vtkgenericvertexattributemapping</compoundname>
    <title>vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkrendering_1sec_vtkrendering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Rendering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping stores mapping between data arrays and generic vertex attributes. It is used by vtkPainterPolyDataMapper to pass the mappings to the painter which rendering the attributes. .SECTION Thanks Support for generic vertex attributes in VTK was contributed in collaboration with Stephane Ploix at EDF.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkGenericVertexAttributeMapping = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AddMapping (string attributeName, string arrayName, int fieldAssociation, int component)</computeroutput> - Select a data array from the point/cell data and map it to a generic vertex attribute. Note that indices change when a mapping is added/removed.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AddMapping (int unit, string arrayName, int fieldAssociation, int component)</computeroutput> - Select a data array and use it as multitexture texture coordinates. Note the texture unit parameter should correspond to the texture unit set on the texture.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>bool = obj.RemoveMapping (string attributeName)</computeroutput> - Remove a vertex attribute mapping.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.RemoveAllMappings ()</computeroutput> - Remove all mappings.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetNumberOfMappings ()</computeroutput> - Get number of mapppings.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetAttributeName (int index)</computeroutput> - Get the attribute name at the given index.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetArrayName (int index)</computeroutput> - Get the array name at the given index.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetFieldAssociation (int index)</computeroutput> - Get the field association at the given index.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetComponent (int index)</computeroutput> - Get the component no. at the given index.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetTextureUnit (int index)</computeroutput> - Get the component no. at the given index.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
