<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkrendering_vtklodprop3d" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkrendering_vtklodprop3d</compoundname>
    <title>vtkLODProp3D</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkrendering_1sec_vtkrendering" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Rendering Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>vtkLODProp3D is a class to support level of detail rendering for Prop3D. Any number of mapper/property/texture items can be added to this object. Render time will be measured, and will be used to select a LOD based on the AllocatedRenderTime of this Prop3D. Depending on the type of the mapper/property, a vtkActor or a vtkVolume will be created behind the scenes.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkLODProp3D, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkLODProp3D
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkLODProp3D has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkLODProp3D class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkLODProp3D = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkLODProp3D = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput>  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetBounds ()</computeroutput> - Standard vtkProp method to get 3D bounds of a 3D prop  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.GetBounds (double bounds[6])</computeroutput> - Standard vtkProp method to get 3D bounds of a 3D prop  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, vtkProperty p, vtkProperty back, vtkTexture t, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, vtkProperty p, vtkTexture t, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, vtkProperty p, vtkProperty back, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, vtkProperty p, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, vtkTexture t, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkMapper m, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkAbstractVolumeMapper m, vtkVolumeProperty p, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.AddLOD (vtkAbstractVolumeMapper m, double time)</computeroutput> - Add a level of detail with a given mapper, property, backface property, texture, and guess of rendering time. The property and texture fields can be set to NULL (the other methods are included for script access where null variables are not allowed). The time field can be set to 0.0 indicating that no initial guess for rendering time is being supplied. The returned integer value is an ID that can be used later to delete this LOD, or set it as the selected LOD.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetNumberOfLODs ()</computeroutput> - Get the current number of LODs.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetCurrentIndex ()</computeroutput> - Get the current index, used to determine the ID of the next LOD that is added. Useful for guessing what IDs have been used (with NumberOfLODs, without depending on the constructor initialization to 1000.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.RemoveLOD (int id)</computeroutput> - Delete a level of detail given an ID. This is the ID returned by the AddLOD method  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODProperty (int id, vtkProperty p)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the property of an LOD. Since the LOD could be a volume or an actor, you have to pass in the pointer to the property to get it. The returned property will be NULL if the id is not valid, or the property is of the wrong type for the corresponding Prop3D.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODProperty (int id, vtkVolumeProperty p)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the property of an LOD. Since the LOD could be a volume or an actor, you have to pass in the pointer to the property to get it. The returned property will be NULL if the id is not valid, or the property is of the wrong type for the corresponding Prop3D.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODMapper (int id, vtkMapper m)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the mapper of an LOD. Since the LOD could be a volume or an actor, you have to pass in the pointer to the mapper to get it. The returned mapper will be NULL if the id is not valid, or the mapper is of the wrong type for the corresponding Prop3D.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODMapper (int id, vtkAbstractVolumeMapper m)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the mapper of an LOD. Since the LOD could be a volume or an actor, you have to pass in the pointer to the mapper to get it. The returned mapper will be NULL if the id is not valid, or the mapper is of the wrong type for the corresponding Prop3D.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkAbstractMapper3D = obj.GetLODMapper (int id)</computeroutput> - Get the LODMapper as an vtkAbstractMapper3D. It is the user&apos;s respondibility to safe down cast this to a vtkMapper or vtkVolumeMapper as appropriate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODBackfaceProperty (int id, vtkProperty t)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the backface property of an LOD. This method is only valid for LOD ids that are Actors (not Volumes)  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODTexture (int id, vtkTexture t)</computeroutput> - Methods to set / get the texture of an LOD. This method is only valid for LOD ids that are Actors (not Volumes)  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.EnableLOD (int id)</computeroutput> - Enable / disable a particular LOD. If it is disabled, it will not be used during automatic selection, but can be selected as the LOD if automatic LOD selection is off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.DisableLOD (int id)</computeroutput> - Enable / disable a particular LOD. If it is disabled, it will not be used during automatic selection, but can be selected as the LOD if automatic LOD selection is off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsLODEnabled (int id)</computeroutput> - Enable / disable a particular LOD. If it is disabled, it will not be used during automatic selection, but can be selected as the LOD if automatic LOD selection is off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetLODLevel (int id, double level)</computeroutput> - Set the level of a particular LOD. When a LOD is selected for rendering because it has the largest render time that fits within the allocated time, all LOD are then checked to see if any one can render faster but has a lower (more resolution/better) level. This quantity is a double to ensure that a level can be inserted between 2 and 3.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetLODLevel (int id)</computeroutput> - Set the level of a particular LOD. When a LOD is selected for rendering because it has the largest render time that fits within the allocated time, all LOD are then checked to see if any one can render faster but has a lower (more resolution/better) level. This quantity is a double to ensure that a level can be inserted between 2 and 3.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetLODIndexLevel (int index)</computeroutput> - Set the level of a particular LOD. When a LOD is selected for rendering because it has the largest render time that fits within the allocated time, all LOD are then checked to see if any one can render faster but has a lower (more resolution/better) level. This quantity is a double to ensure that a level can be inserted between 2 and 3.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetLODEstimatedRenderTime (int id)</computeroutput> - Access method that can be used to find out the estimated render time (the thing used to select an LOD) for a given LOD ID or index. Value is returned in seconds.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj.GetLODIndexEstimatedRenderTime (int index)</computeroutput> - Access method that can be used to find out the estimated render time (the thing used to select an LOD) for a given LOD ID or index. Value is returned in seconds.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetAutomaticLODSelection (int )</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticLODSelectionMinValue ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticLODSelectionMaxValue ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticLODSelection ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AutomaticLODSelectionOn ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AutomaticLODSelectionOff ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetSelectedLODID (int )</computeroutput> - Set the id of the LOD that is to be drawn when automatic LOD selection is turned off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetSelectedLODID ()</computeroutput> - Set the id of the LOD that is to be drawn when automatic LOD selection is turned off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetLastRenderedLODID ()</computeroutput> - Get the ID of the previously (during the last render) selected LOD index  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetPickLODID (void )</computeroutput> - Get the ID of the appropriate pick LOD index  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.GetActors (vtkPropCollection )</computeroutput> - For some exporters and other other operations we must be able to collect all the actors or volumes. These methods are used in that process.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.GetVolumes (vtkPropCollection )</computeroutput> - For some exporters and other other operations we must be able to collect all the actors or volumes. These methods are used in that process.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetSelectedPickLODID (int id)</computeroutput> - Set the id of the LOD that is to be used for picking when automatic LOD pick selection is turned off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetSelectedPickLODID ()</computeroutput> - Set the id of the LOD that is to be used for picking when automatic LOD pick selection is turned off.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetAutomaticPickLODSelection (int )</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticPickLODSelectionMinValue ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticPickLODSelectionMaxValue ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.GetAutomaticPickLODSelection ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AutomaticPickLODSelectionOn ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.AutomaticPickLODSelectionOff ()</computeroutput> - Turn on / off automatic selection of picking LOD. This is on by default. If it is off, then the SelectedLODID is rendered regardless of rendering time or desired update rate.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.ShallowCopy (vtkProp prop)</computeroutput> - Shallow copy of this vtkLODProp3D.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
