<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkwidgets_vtktextwidget" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkwidgets_vtktextwidget</compoundname>
    <title>vtkTextWidget</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkwidgets_1sec_vtkwidgets" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Widget Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>This class provides support for interactively placing text on the 2D overlay plane. The text is defined by an instance of vtkTextActor. It uses the event bindings of its superclass (vtkBorderWidget). In addition, when the text is selected, the widget emits a WidgetActivateEvent that observers can watch for. This is useful for opening GUI dialogues to adjust font characteristics, etc. (Please see the superclass for a description of event bindings.)</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkTextWidget, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkTextWidget
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkTextWidget has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkTextWidget class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput> - Standard VTK methods.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput> - Standard VTK methods.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkTextWidget = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput> - Standard VTK methods.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkTextWidget = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput> - Standard VTK methods.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetRepresentation (vtkTextRepresentation r)</computeroutput> - Specify a vtkTextActor to manage. This is a convenient, alternative method to specify the representation for the widget (i.e., used instead of SetRepresentation()). It internally creates a vtkTextRepresentation and then invokes vtkTextRepresentation::SetTextActor().  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetTextActor (vtkTextActor textActor)</computeroutput> - Specify a vtkTextActor to manage. This is a convenient, alternative method to specify the representation for the widget (i.e., used instead of SetRepresentation()). It internally creates a vtkTextRepresentation and then invokes vtkTextRepresentation::SetTextActor().  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkTextActor = obj.GetTextActor ()</computeroutput> - Specify a vtkTextActor to manage. This is a convenient, alternative method to specify the representation for the widget (i.e., used instead of SetRepresentation()). It internally creates a vtkTextRepresentation and then invokes vtkTextRepresentation::SetTextActor().  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.CreateDefaultRepresentation ()</computeroutput> - Create the default widget representation if one is not set.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
