<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.1.1">
  <compounddef id="vtkwidgets_vtkimageactorpointplacer" kind="page">
    <compoundname>vtkwidgets_vtkimageactorpointplacer</compoundname>
    <title>vtkImageActorPointPlacer</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Section: <ref refid="sec_vtkwidgets_1sec_vtkwidgets" kindref="member">Visualization Toolkit Widget Classes</ref> </para><sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Usage">
<title>Usage</title>
<para>This PointPlacer is used to constrain the placement of points on the supplied image actor. Additionally, you may set bounds to restrict the placement of the points. The placement of points will then be constrained to lie not only on the ImageActor but also within the bounds specified. If no bounds are specified, they may lie anywhere on the supplied ImageActor.</para><para>To create an instance of class vtkImageActorPointPlacer, simply invoke its constructor as follows <verbatim>  obj = vtkImageActorPointPlacer
</verbatim> </para></sect1>
<sect1 id="vtkwidgets_vtkxyplotwidget_1Methods">
<title>Methods</title>
<para>The class vtkImageActorPointPlacer has several methods that can be used. They are listed below. Note that the documentation is translated automatically from the VTK sources, and may not be completely intelligible. When in doubt, consult the VTK website. In the methods listed below, <computeroutput>obj</computeroutput> is an instance of the vtkImageActorPointPlacer class. <itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>string = obj.GetClassName ()</computeroutput> - Standard methods for instances of this class.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.IsA (string name)</computeroutput> - Standard methods for instances of this class.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkImageActorPointPlacer = obj.NewInstance ()</computeroutput> - Standard methods for instances of this class.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkImageActorPointPlacer = obj.SafeDownCast (vtkObject o)</computeroutput> - Standard methods for instances of this class.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.ComputeWorldPosition (vtkRenderer ren, double displayPos[2], double worldPos[3], double worldOrient[9])</computeroutput> - Given and renderer and a display position in pixels, find a world position and orientation. In this class an internal vtkBoundedPlanePointPlacer is used to compute the world position and orientation. The internal placer is set to use the plane of the image actor and the bounds of the image actor as the constraints for placing points.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.ComputeWorldPosition (vtkRenderer ren, double displayPos[2], double refWorldPos[2], double worldPos[3], double worldOrient[9])</computeroutput> - This method is identical to the one above since the reference position is ignored by the bounded plane point placer.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.ValidateWorldPosition (double worldPos[3])</computeroutput> - This method validates a world position by checking to see if the world position is valid according to the constraints of the internal placer (essentially - is this world position on the image?)  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.ValidateWorldPosition (double worldPos[3], double worldOrient[9])</computeroutput> - This method is identical to the one above since the bounded plane point placer ignores orientation  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.UpdateWorldPosition (vtkRenderer ren, double worldPos[3], double worldOrient[9])</computeroutput> - Update the world position and orientation according the the current constraints of the placer. Will be called by the representation when it notices that this placer has been modified.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>int = obj.UpdateInternalState ()</computeroutput> - A method for configuring the internal placer according to the constraints of the image actor. Called by the representation to give the placer a chance to update itself, which may cause the MTime to change, which would then cause the representation to update all of its points  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetImageActor (vtkImageActor )</computeroutput> - Set / get the reference vtkImageActor used to place the points. An image actor must be set for this placer to work. An internal bounded plane point placer is created and set to match the bounds of the displayed image.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>vtkImageActor = obj.GetImageActor ()</computeroutput> - Set / get the reference vtkImageActor used to place the points. An image actor must be set for this placer to work. An internal bounded plane point placer is created and set to match the bounds of the displayed image.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetBounds (double , double , double , double , double , double )</computeroutput> - Optionally, you may set bounds to restrict the placement of the points. The placement of points will then be constrained to lie not only on the ImageActor but also within the bounds specified. If no bounds are specified, they may lie anywhere on the supplied ImageActor.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetBounds (double a[6])</computeroutput> - Optionally, you may set bounds to restrict the placement of the points. The placement of points will then be constrained to lie not only on the ImageActor but also within the bounds specified. If no bounds are specified, they may lie anywhere on the supplied ImageActor.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>double = obj. GetBounds ()</computeroutput> - Optionally, you may set bounds to restrict the placement of the points. The placement of points will then be constrained to lie not only on the ImageActor but also within the bounds specified. If no bounds are specified, they may lie anywhere on the supplied ImageActor.  </para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para><computeroutput>obj.SetWorldTolerance (double s)</computeroutput> - Set the world tolerance. This propagates it to the internal BoundedPlanePointPlacer.  </para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para></sect1>
    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
